http://www.swrr.co.uk/privacy-policy

Group Bookings – Covid 19
Club Night: Road and TrackWednesday NIghts – road groups and coached track
Transition GroupOn our Wednesday club night
Marathon TrainingWinter – Sunday Mornings
GWR TrainingJuly to September – Sunday Mornings
Sunday RunsVaried on and off road runs throughout the year
Quay2FitnessAn affiliated group that runs on Monday evenings
Results & Prizes
PRIVACY STATEMENTAbout usSouth West Road Runners (SWRR) is a sports club affiliated to England Athletics (EA), club affiliation registration number 2658579.  SWRR is the ‘data controller’ under data protection legislation.  In this document, the pronoun ‘we’ is used interchangeably with ‘SWRR’.What data we collectWhen you become a member, volunteer, coach or official of SWRR, we will collect certain information about you which will include your name, date of birth, gender, athlete registration number (EA number), email address, postal address, telephone number, names of the EA-affiliated clubs which you belong to and details of any coaching or officiating licences, DBS licences, and competition results.  This information is collectively known as Athletics Data.  We will also collect the name, address and contact number of an emergency contact nominated by you.We may also collect other information for the benefit of SWRR, such as willingness to volunteer for certain activities.  You may opt not to provide this information if you wish.Why we collect itWe will collect and process your Athletics Data for the purposes of registering you as a member of SWRR and administering your involvement in the sport.  We will process it on the basis of legitimate interests.  These are the interests of registering you as a member and to facilitate your participation in the sport.How long we will keep itWe will retain your Athletics Data for such time as you are an athlete registered with us or a volunteer, coach or official involved with us and will then delete your information  as follows:Athletics Data: six months after the end of the financial year for which you last paid to be a member (e.g. if you have paid for membership up to 31st March 2019 and do not renew thereafter, your data will be deleted with effect from 30th September 2019).Membership forms: as above, six months after expiry of membershipData relating to club races/competitions e.g. First Chance, Drogo:  12 months after the relevant race or competition Your rightsYou have the following rights under data protection legislation:-To access a copy of the information held about youTo object to the processing of your personal information if this causes or would be likely to cause damage or distressTo prevent processing for direct marketingTo object to decisions being taken by automated meansIn certain circumstances, to have inaccurate personal information corrected, blocked, erased or destroyedTo claim compensation for damages caused by breach of data protection legislationSharing your dataWe may share your Athletics Data with athletics partners such as UK Athletics, EA, other Home Country Athletics organisations, selected members of the National Council, Regional Council, County Athletics Association, Area Athletics Association, and third-party data managers that we appoint as data processors as part of administering your involvement in the sport.  Your data may also appear on Power of 10 which is a body that provides a comprehensive results and rankings service for the sport of athletics.We will not transfer your data to any other third parties without obtaining your consent and, where possible, will anonymise your data before sharing.  We will also not share any other personal data you provide to us that is not Athletics Data.ComplaintsIf you have any concerns or complaints in relation to how SWRR collects and or processes your personal data, you should contact a member of the General Committee in the first instance.  The matter will be referred to the most appropriate officer which may be the Club Secretary, the Membership Secretary, or the Welfare Officer as the Committee sees fit.  If you are dissatisfied with how your concern or complaint is dealt with by SWRR, you have the right to report your concern/complaint to the Information Commissioners Office, www.ico.org.ukPublication and review of Privacy PolicyThis policy will be circulated to all members immediately following its creation and to coincide with the coming into effect of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).  It will also be published on SWRR’s website www.swrr.co.ukThis policy will be made available to any member on request to the Club Secretary whose contact details are on the website.The General Committee of SWRR will review this policy at least once a year, and will notify the membership of any amendments.
